welcome to another darktable tutorial in
欢迎来到中的另一个暗表教程
this video we'll look at styles and
在这段视频中 我们将了解样式和
presets and learn how to use those to
预设 并学习如何使用这些预设
speed up our workflow and make more
加快我们的工作流程 创造更多
professional edits in darktable we've
我们在暗表中进行了专业编辑
learned in the past that we can just
我们在过去了解到 我们可以
copy the entire history stack from an
将整个历史记录堆栈从
image and apply it to another one that's
图像并将其应用于另一个
similar to how Styles will work but
与Styles的工作原理类似 但
instead of having to hold all those
而不是必须拿着所有这些
changes in our clipboard and only be
在我们的剪贴板中进行更改 并且
able to apply one specific history stack
能够应用一个特定的历史记录堆栈
at a time styles is right down here
在某个时候 Style就在这里
right below the history stack and what
就在历史堆栈的下面 还有什么
Styles lets us do is save a certain all
样式让我们做的是保存特定的所有
the changes all the modules and their
更改了所有模块及其
settings we can save that so we'll click
设置我们可以保存它 这样我们就可以点击
create and it brings up this box and we
创建 它会打开这个框 我们
can just call this cool black and white
可以说这是很酷的黑白
and go to save and now we can apply that
然后转到保存 现在我们可以应用
to images when we're in the darkroom and
当我们在暗室里的时候
doing our edits so the other way to do
这样做我们的编辑是另一种方式
this is we can just come up here like
这就是我们可以像这样来这里
we've learned in the past and go copy we
我们学到了过去的东西 然后去复制我们
copy all of them and then click on the
将它们全部复制 然后单击
image we want to apply them to and go
我们要将它们应用到的图像 然后开始
paste so this is not styles this is just
粘贴 所以这不是样式 这只是
copying the modules with their settings
复制模块及其设置
and applying them to another image
并将它们应用于另一幅图像
whereas style is once we've done this
而风格是一旦我们做到了这一点
once we've created a style and we go
一旦我们创造了一种风格 我们就可以
into the darkroom we can select any
进入暗室 我们可以选择
image like this one here and then we can
像这里这样的图像 然后我们就可以
just come down it's this teeny little
下来就好了 就是这个小小的
icon and we click on this and it brings
图标 我们点击它 它就会带来
up a dialog and says what style are at
打开对话 说出你的风格是什么
contact of the list and I only have one
名单上的联系人 我只有一个
right now this one that I just created
现在 这是我刚刚创建的
but if we click on it it applies
但如果我们点击它 它就会应用
everything that was on that image which
那张照片上的所有东西
is only it actually duplicated some of
只是它实际上复制了一些
that stuff over there but it basically
那里的那些东西 但基本上
applied all that to the two here let's
将所有这些应用到这两个上 让我们
go look at another one so I have one
去看看另一个 这样我就有一个了
that I made some changes to earlier and
我之前对它做了一些修改
this one does have a little bit so I did
这件确实有一点 所以我做了
some color correction we have some split
一些色彩校正 我们有一些分裂
toning and me not covered correction I
色调和我未涵盖更正I
did some monochrome I did some split
我做了一些单色的分割
toning a little bit of I put a vignette
稍微调一下我就放了个小插曲
around it so let's just maybe if I want
所以如果我想的话
to replicate this look or have this be
复制这种外观 或者让它成为
like a signature look for pictures that
就像签名一样寻找那些
I do
我知道
I could come into the light table and
我可以走进灯光桌
then go to this drop-down here for
然后转到此处的下拉列表
styles and I'll just go to create oh I
斯泰尔斯和我要去创造哦我
want one make sure I'm selected on that
我想要一个 确保我被选上了
image which I am and click on create and
映像我是谁 然后点击创建和
now I'll call this one TJ cool filter
现在我把这个叫做TJ Cool Filter
and now this click save and now this is
现在点击保存 现在这是
saved here so now I have two different
保存在这里 所以现在我有两个不同的
options so now when I'm in the darkroom
所以现在当我在暗室里的时候
if ever I want to see just very quickly
如果我想快点看的话
I wonder what this image here would look
我想知道这张照片会是什么样子
like with my cool filter settings I can
就像我的酷滤镜设置一样 我可以
just click this here and go to TJ cool
只需点击此处并转到TJ Cool
filter and it adds all of those modules
过滤器 它添加了所有这些模块
with all of those settings to them so
在所有这些设置的情况下
that's Styles now that's different from
这就是Styles 这不同于
presets what the presets let us do is if
预置这些预置允许我们做的是
we apply something like a vignette for
我们用一些类似于小插曲的东西
example we want to apply that to here
例如 我们希望将其应用于此处
there's these three little lines and
有这三条小线
we've looked at this a little bit before
我们以前已经看过这个问题了
actually we click on these lines and we
实际上 我们点击这些行 然后我们
have some different options so here's
有一些不同的选择 所以这里是
the one that I created called dark VIN
我创建的名为Dark VIN的
it creates a very strong dark vignette
它创造了一种非常强烈的黑暗氛围
around the image and there's one that's
在图像周围 有一个是
built in called Lomo and it just looks
内置了名为Lomo的设备 看起来
like this not quite as strong but it
像这样没有那么强烈 但它
adjusts all these different changes but
调整了所有这些不同的更改 但
it's only for this module so it's not
它只适用于这个模块 所以它不是
applying a bunch of different modules to
将一系列不同的模块应用于
an image it's just changing the
一个形象 它只是改变了
different input values for this
此对象的不同输入值
particular module so if we notice we
特定模块 所以如果我们注意到
come down here to soften there are no
来到这里来软化这里没有
presets and if we click on vignette it's
预置 如果我们点击Vignette
going to have presets specific to the
将具有特定于
Finn yelling we can go to like our tone
芬兰人大喊大叫我们可以去喜欢我们的语气
curve has some different ones there like
Curve在那里有一些不同的 比如
a high contrast we can click on and see
我们可以点击并查看高对比度
what that looks like these are built in
这些看起来像是内置的
there's a linear so we can see and then
这是一条直线 所以我们可以看到
we can see what they look like do we
我们可以看到他们的样子 是吗？
have a medium contrast which the curve
具有中等对比度的曲线
looks like this and it makes these
看起来像这样 它使这些
changes and if we want to adjust this
如果我们想要调整这一点
and make our own custom one we can do
让我们自己定制一个我们可以做的
that as well we just get it to where we
我们也只是把它带到我们想要的地方
the input to the way that we like it we
我们喜欢它的方式的输入是我们
click on these three lines and go to
点击这三行 然后转到
store new preset and it comes up with a
存储新的预设值 它会显示一个
dialog so I can call this one extreme
对话 所以我可以称之为极端
and go okay and now we can apply that to
好的 现在我们可以把它应用到
any image we want we open up a new image
任何我们想要的形象 我们都会打开一个新形象
and we go to extreme and we see how that
我们走到了极端 我们看到了
adjusts this image and how it makes it
调整此图像及其制作方式
look to delete a preset if we want to
如果我们想要删除预设 请查看
get rid of that extreme we can click on
摆脱我们可以点击的极端
it and just go to apply it first and
它和只是去应用它首先和
then we just go to delete this preset it
那我们就直接去删除这个预置吧
comes up with a dialog we just say yes
想出一个对话 我们只是说好的
and now that preset is no longer there
现在那个预置已经不在那里了
and that's the same with the Styles
对Styles来说也是如此
we'll go back into light table we can
我们会回到灯光桌 我们可以
delete a style by just clicking on it
只需单击样式即可将其删除
and going to delete and then that style
删除该样式 然后删除该样式
would no longer be available one preset
将不再提供一个预置
that we've used in the past that before
我们以前用过的那个
we kind of talked about presets are the
我们谈到了预置是
presets for the base curve based on
基本曲线的预设基于
different cameras and so these are put
不同的摄像头 所以这些都放在
in by default and again we can make our
在默认情况下 我们可以再次使我们的
own and save our own custom preset if we
拥有并保存我们自己的自定义预设 如果
want to and so that's just a great
想要 所以这是一个很好的
powerful feature using these presets and
使用这些预设和功能的强大功能
using styles in the next tutorial we'll
在下一教程中使用样式 我们将
learn how to create our own style based
学习如何创建我们自己的风格
off of an existing image so if we want
所以如果我们想要
to have this sort of look and feel and
拥有这样的外观和感觉
apply it to a picture of our own that's
把它应用到我们自己的一张照片上
just a picture I downloaded we'll learn
只是我下载的一张照片 我们会知道的
how to take the colors from that using
如何使用它来获取颜色
this color mapping module and so that
此颜色映射模块 因此
should be a lot of fun will take like a
应该会很有趣 就像一个
sky picture like this and hopefully be
像这样的天空图片 希望是
able to make it look apply that to a sky
能够让它看起来像是应用到天空中
picture that I've taken that's not
我拍的那张照片不是
nearly as cool thanks for watching go
差不多一样酷 感谢收看围棋
ahead and leave your questions and
把你的问题留在前面
comments below if you have any and we'll
如果你有任何评论 我们会
catch you in the next video
在下一个视频中看到你